The rules keep changing.
I've been rehearsing every possible outcome.
Once this thought arises, there is no more room for right or wrong.
I am resolved to sever this flood
so that my soul can break free from mediocrity,
from loneliness and distinction.
One more step and you'll fall into madness.
Don't fall down.
I look towards the top.
Chase !
Refined to perfection.
Never retreat, no matter the danger.
I dare to defy the heavens !
Always overcome the obstacles,
ignite the seas with blood,
bloom through trials and tribulations.
Even the sharpest thorns
will be reduced into ashes.
What is there to fear ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
We climbed mountains
to see how vast the heavens and earth are.
The heavens and the earth
really are so vast...
We watched rivers
to understand their surging might.
Dad,
these waves won't stop us !
Good !
We faced the seas
to grasp their boundlessness.
Dad,
I will spend my life
accompanying you.
Even in death.
If there is a next life,
even if we are no longer father and son,
I'll never forget you !
8 years later
8 years of traveling mountains and rivers
washed his soul clean.
The resentment is almost gone,
only a sliver of it remains.
Medicine and spells are useless now.
Since it's deeply rooted in his soul,
only time can extinguish it.
Dad,
I remember hearing when I was little
that there was immortal mist on Qilian Peak.
One breath of it would keep you healthy for 10 years.
Back then I thought
that one day
I wanted you to bring me here.
It's so beautiful...
Is...
Is it an Immortal ?
Yes.
Dad...
Are you...
Are you an Immortal too ?
Not exactly an Immortal,
I'm just an ordinary cultivator.
Grandpa Sun,
we've come to see you.
Dad and I have traveled to many places.
We've seen huge mountains,
big rivers,
and the boundless sea.
Dad...
Why won't you let me learn
the Immortal spells Grandpa Sun left behind ?
Because the life of a cultivator
doesn't suit you.
Do you mean that you
you want me to live an ordinary life
instead of following your footsteps
and becoming a cultivator ?
Is that it ?
What if
I don't agree ?
Don't ever
mention this matter again.
Aside from cultivation,
I can give you
everything in this world.
Father,
only by cultivating the Dao
can I stay by your side longer.
I told you
that you are not suited for cultivation.
Why is that ?
I understand now...
Father.
The reason Dad won't let me cultivate
must be because the cultivation world is too dangerous.
His cultivation is low
and he can't fully protect me.
Dad must have endured too much suffering
and is afraid I'll be bullied.
Dad,
I was wrong.
Vast Water City
Planet Ran Yun
From now on,
we will live in this city.
We will
buy a house soon.
Qing Yi
Sun Family member
Qi Condensation
Are you okay ?
Thank you, brother.
Yun Wufeng
Yun Family member
Qi Condensation
Dad,
this place isn't bad.
After being used to the mountains, rivers, and the sea,
seeing this lively big city
feels like
I'm suddenly re-entering the world.
Junior Sister Qing Yi,
that foolish boy looks amusing.
Perhaps it's his first time in Vast Water City.
He's putting on airs about having seen mountains and rivers
and spouting nonsense about re-entering the world.
Is it funny ?
Why wouldn't it be funny ?
Qing Yi is usually
cold towards everyone.
But when that man walked in,
she actually looked at him.
With such looks,
if you were born a woman,
you would've been a jade beauty.
What a pity !
You unfortunately were born a man.
However,
maybe you can still become a prostitute.
With such looks,
if you were born a man,
you would've been graceful and handsome.
What a pity...
You unfortunately were born an animal.
Sun Hai
Sun Family member
Core Formation
How rude !
On behalf of your Elders,
I will cripple your arms
to teach you a lesson !
No !
My Golden Core...
Master !
I don’t need you
to discipline my son.
You !
You're also a cultivator !
On Planet Ran Yun,
offending the Sun Family
is the same as...
Senior !
We were reckless in handling this matter,
please have mercy.
Young lady,
is your name Qing Yi ?
I am Wang Ping.
Are you also a cultivator ?
I haven't reached Foundation Establishment,
I'm not yet a true cultivator.
What happened today
was truly our fault.
However,
my master has already crushed the jade slip,
so they will probably arrive soon !
You need to leave quickly !
Sun Zi
Sun Family member
Middle stage Nascent Soul
Sun Shang
Sun Family member
Peak Late stage Nascent Soul
Sun Wu
Sun Family member
Middle stage Nascent Soul
Grandmaster Sun !
Uncle...
It was him...
He harmed me !
A mortal ?
This child has exceptional talent !
These two
are definitely not as simple as they appear.
You acted ruthlessly by destroying
the Golden Core of a member of my family.
Do you really think my Sun Family will just sit idly !?
Ping'er,
let's go.
Stop here !
The matter is not settled,
how dare you leave !?
No spell, no technique...
This is...
pure Dao comprehension !?
Just this once.
Don't let it happen again.
What happened today was truly our fault.
That girl named Qing Yi
seems like a good person.
This courtyard is very large
and has quite a few rooms.
Wang
Mansion
When the previous owner sold the house,
Welcome home, Master.
they left behind some maids and servants.
Master...
This
Young Master...
is our new home.
What's wrong ?
Dad,
are you acquainted with
the Sun Family ?
I had some encounters with them.
The Sun Family seems
to be very powerful here in Vast Water City.
If they really come to settle the score,
what should we do ?
Sun Family Branch Main Residence
Vast Water City
Junior did not mishear.
That man indeed said
"Just this once.
Don't let it happen again."
It seems someone has no regard for the Sun Family !
Sun Kaiping
Sun Family Branch Elder
What was
this person's surname ?
We don't know.
Junior Nephew Qing Yi spoke briefly
with those two.
Maybe she knows.
Do you know ?
Junior doesn't know.
You dare to lie to me ?
How audacious !
Junior
really doesn't know !
Enough !
I have already reported this to the main family.
In a few days,
a Soul Transformation Elder will come to handle it.
As for you, an outsider by blood,
you will be confined
for your favoritism of outsiders.
We'll deal with you later.
Wang
Mansion
Family Head.
Named Wang ?
When I probed with Divine Sense,
I found nothing unusual.
Sun Qiming of the Sun Family
pays respects to fellow cultivator.
The master has
instructed you
to leave.
He won't even see us ?
Indeed !
How dare he make the Family Head wait ?
How outrageous !
This is truly outrageous !
Such an arrogant attitude,
do you really think the Sun family is that weak !?
That familiar Ascendant aura...
It's...
It's him !
Junior deserves to be punished
for disturbing Senior's cultivation.
Junior
will leave immediately !
Go !
Ping'er,
you lived 19 years of an ordinary life in Fallen Moon Village.
For 8 years you experienced traveling through
mountains, rivers, and seas.
A human's life,
the joys and sorrows,
poverty and riches, nobility and peasantry...
You should experience all of it
for your life to be complete.
After that,
I promise you 30 years of wealth and honor.
Dad,
are you and the Sun Family
only acquaintances ?
Your father once promised
to protect their family for 100 years.
I didn't expect Father's cultivation to be so high
that even the leader of the Sun Family would cower in fear before you.
I originally thought
you couldn't protect me
and that it was the reason you didn't want me to cultivate.
I was wrong.
But I truly cannot understand
why Father refuses to let me cultivate !
I told you,
you're not suited for it.
30 years of wealth and honor...
Is that your compensation
for not letting me cultivate ?
Yes.
Father,
what is true wealth and honor ?
What kind of wealth and honor do you want ?
You once taught me
that a person should defy the heavens
and refuse to be crushed by the heavens and the earth.
Climb mountains when you encounter them,
cross rivers when you encounter them,
cross the seas when you encounter them.
Never give in
when facing the heavens and the earth !
Since you won't let me cultivate
then I will become
the supreme ruler among mortals !
If that is what you want,
very well.
I don't want things to be handed to me.
I will conquer the world
by myself !
You've grown up.
Very well.
Father,
you can give me everything
so why won't you let me cultivate ?
I am not suited
to cultivate the Dao...
But I promised you back then
that I would stay by your side forever !
Father,
you are too lonely...
Protect him
on his journey.
Ping'er,
it's not that I won't let you cultivate.
It's that you can't cultivate.
One day, you will understand.
But I hope that day
comes as late as possible.
Even
that it never comes at all.
All members of the Sun Family, listen to me !
Don't step within 1000 zhang of the Wang Mansion !
Those who do
will be crippled
and be expelled from the family !
Fa...
Family Head,
who is that person ?
Who is he ?
He is someone before whom even our Ancestor
would kneel to and bow with respect.
He is the benefactor
our Sun Family owes its situation to !
And you dared to provoke him !?
Could it be that person...
Senior Xu Mu ?
You nearly brought a disaster
upon our Sun Family.
I will tell this matter
to the Yun Family Head.
You
should better watch out.
This is all because of you !
If you hadn't looked at that boy a few times,
I wouldn't have provoked him !
If it weren't for you,
I wouldn't have offended Xu Mu's son !
This is all because of you !
Qing Yi,
let's flee.
If the Family Head finds out about this,
they will beat me to death !
Now that you've also been expelled from the Sun Family,
your cultivation is sealed
and you're no different from a mortal !
We are a better match now !
In this vast world,
no one will be able to find us !
Junior Qing Yi
pays respects to Senior.
Your talent
is pretty good.
Spend a lifetime with Ping'er
and I'll give you Nascent Soul cultivation.
Are you willing ?
I am Wang Ping.
Are you also a cultivator ?
Junior
is willing.
Over 800 years of cultivation
and this is the first time I've gotten drunk
on mundane wine...
Father,
take care.
Is the wine too strong ?
Or is it
that my heart
is too heavy ?
Karma...
So this is
karma ?
Go ahead and take a look
on the other side of the mountain.
See if the wind is blowing
across the sea.
A lush tree always grows
from a tender shoot.
That tree shields you
from half of the cold.
The scent of the herbs and the smoke
have drifted away from the stove
whose fire has warmed up
half of your lifetime.
I watch you smile
as you run back to me.
That cry, however,
came out slowly.
I'll take you on a journey through the mortal world,
as autumn fades and spring returns.
A few snowflakes have fallen from the eaves,
I hope this letter finds you well.
I’ll wait for you under the locust tree,
having weathered the storms of our journey so far.
Looking back, the smell of the food
hasn't changed.
Take your time.
I’ve walked through this world with you
and listened to the joys and sorrows of the mountains.
As I count the falling leaves, as spring warms,
another year has flown by.
I’ll wait for you under the locust tree,
having weathered the storms of our journey so far.
Looking back, the smell of the food
hasn't changed.
Take your time.